

IMAN NADEEM

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

CONTACT ME AT

iman.nadeem.825@gmail.com



imannadeem825.github.io



github.com/imannadeem825



in linkedin.com/in/iman-nadeem

SKILLS

HTML | CSS | JavaScript | React | C# .Net | JSON server | SQL | Git

ABOUT ME

Before beginning my journey as a software developer, I've worked in customer service positions and in the medical field. I also have been a musician for most of my life. I come from a family of physicians and have come to appreciate and understand what it means to serve people, and make a huge impact on their lives, not just "help" them. People come first in my life, and I believe that value has led me to develop strong interpersonal and communication skills. I naturally gravitate towards opportunities that can challenge me intellectually, allow me to be creative, and give me a chance to invest in any of my passions. After hearing from friends that software development could fulfill all those desires, I knew I had to give it a shot. I'm so happy I took a step towards a career that not only keeps me on my toes every day, but also lets me be part of a team that can only accomplish its goals when its members are truly working together.

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

Full Stack Software Developer

November 2020 - May 2021

- Intensive, full-time software development program learning full-stack technologies by creating applications in group and individual settings
 - Built single page applications using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and React
 - Hands-on, fast-paced simulated work environment, for both individual assignments and team projects
 - SQL Server database, writing database scripts, querying databases
 - Experience with remote collaboration
 - Git and GitHub for version control

Personal Projects

Memo to Demo, Front-End Capstone

- · Memo to Demo is an application for songwriter-producers to organize their original content into task lists. It allows a user to enter information about songs that are in progress, and have all songs display in a list. Then, a user can add a demo to be completed that corresponds with a song in the songs list. Tracks to be completed can be added to each demo. Users can update and delete any information in the application.
 - Single page, full CRUD React application utilizing React hooks to manage
 - JSON-server used as local database
 - Styling with CSS3

Care On Command, Back-End Capstone

- Care On Command is an application for cancer patients to track and self-report their symptoms to their providers on a daily basis. When patients are undergoing cancer treatment, they often are so sick that they need to be in touch with their providers many days out of the week, because certain symptoms left untreated can cause further complications. Users are prompted to report if they are experiencing certain symptoms, and if so, will be further prompted to report the severity of the symptom and leave a comment if desired. If a user reports any symptom being severe, the app will notify them that there is an urgent need to communicate with their provider. They can update and delete these daily reports once saved.
 - Multi page, full CRUD, full-stack application
 - ASP.NET for back-end, React and JavaScript for front-end
 - Firebase user authentication

Group Projects

Nutshell

- A single page social media app with messaging, events, news and a tasks list
 - Individually responsible for tasks list, with delete capability
 - Team collaborated on entity relationship diagram, wireframe and dependency graph
 - Fetched data from local JSON-Server and used browser local and session storage

Tabloid

- A full CRUD ASP.NET application created in two stages, MVC and fullstack, with different groups respectively
- Multi-page blogging platform with posts, comments, categories, tags, user authentication
- SQL Server as database engine
- MVC
 - individually responsible for comments, with CRUD capability
 - Razor templating syntax for view models
- Full-stack
 - Firebase user authentication
 - individually responsible for user profiles

WORK EXPERIENCE

SMILE DIRECT CLUB

Call Center Representative

December 2019 - April 2020

- Received inbound calls for customer care, conducted outbound calls for scheduling of appointments
 - Wrote scripts for live calls and voicemails
 - Worked with Five9, software for inbound and outbound calls

TIFF'S TREATS

Kitchen/Driver

April 2018 - September 2018

- Performed kitchen duties
- Trained new employees
- Drove for delivery orders

SODEXO

Caterer, Belmont University

September 2016 - September 2017

- Performed kitchen duties
- Served patrons
- Created displays
- Moved kitchen equipment
- Fast-paced environment

RESIN8

Sync Licensing/Artist Management intern

Summer 2016

- Entered metadata into system server
- Organized all in-house writer/artist information
- Managed excel documents
- Compiled research on music in TV and film spots as well as in-show music

MIDWEST PULMONARY CONSULTANTS, LLC

Office Assistant/Medical Scribe

Summer 2014, Summer 2015

- Worked one-on-one with patients, documented follow-up visits
- Scanned documents
- Organized and prepared medical charts for billing

LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE AT BELMONT UNIVERSITY

PRISMATICS A CAPPELLA

Vice President

2015 - 2018

- Helped start group, establish constitution and officer roles
- Oversaw recruitment and retention of members
- Helped book rehearsal spaces and performances
- Addressed personal affairs within group
- Oversaw community outreach
- Arranged vocal charts

HOPE COUNCIL

Vice President of Administrative Relations

Fall 2016 - Spring 2017

- Acted as liaison between students and university administration
- Oversaw development of organization
- Helped organized World Culture Festival on campus
- Held and led meetings for general body
- Invited and coordinated with guest speakers
- Organized and held first leadership summit for all diversity organization student leaders

GENDER EQUALITY MOVEMENT

Vice President

2015 - 2017

- Helped start group, establish constitution and officer roles
- Led general body meetings
- Created topics for discussion
- Cultivated relationships with other diversity organizations on campus
- Oversaw member outreach and retention

EDUCATION

BELMONT UNIVERSITY

Bachelor of Music | 2018

Major in Commercial Voice, Songwriting emphasis

- Cum Laude, Honors Scholar
- Omicron Delta Kappa Honor Society
- Senior Thesis "Unorthodox EP"

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

Certificate, Software Development | 2021

Full Stack Software Development